Inventory of the Kingsley Davis Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Data on population by states
  - Georgia--by race, cities, county, and age of mother, 1957-1960 (Folder 15: 8)
  - Hawaii--by county and race, 1957-1960 (Folder 15: 9)
  - Iowa--by county, race, and age of mother, 1957-1960 (Folder 15: 10)
  - Kansas--by county, race, and age of mother, 1957-1960 (Folder 15: 11)
  - Kentucky--by county and race of mother, 1957-1960 (Folder 15: 12)
  - Louisiana--by county--Age of Mother, Race, and Sex of Child, 1957-1960 (Folder 15: 13)
  - Maine--detailed study, 1958 (Folder 15: 14)
  - Alabama--by county, race, and age of mother, 1959-1960 (Folder 15: 15)
  - Florida--by race and county, 1917-1953; 1957-1960 (Folder 15: 16)
  - District of Columbia--number of children-born alive and race, 1950; 1955-1960 (Folder 15: 17)
  - Illinois--by race and county, 1950-1960 (Folder 15: 18)
  - Indiana--by race and county, 1950; 1960 (Folder 15: 19)
- Illegitimacy study, 1930-1962
  - Data, 1930-1960 (Folder 15: 20)
  - Working papers, 1959-1962 (Folder 15: 21)
  - Working file, 1962 (Folder 15: 22)
  - News clippings, 1961-1962 (Folder 15: 23)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Folder 15: 24)
- International Population and Urban Research (IPUR) (Box 16)
  - Demography Department, 1972-1973 (Folder 16: 1)
  - Personnel, 1972-1973 (Folder 16: 2)
  - Publications, 1972-1974 (Folder 16: 3)
- Arno Press, Inc., 1974-1975. (Folder 16: 4)
  The folder is incorrectly labeled ARCO Publishing. Includes photocopies of articles dating to 1846
- Genetics Commission
  - Background and genesis, 1968-1970 (Folder 16: 5-6)
  - Reports, 1970-1972 (Folder 16: 7-8)
  - Transit, 1971 (Folder 16: 9)
- Correspondence
  - Lush, Jay L., 1970 (Folder 16: 10)
  - Hildebrand, Joel H., 1969-1970 (Folder 16: 11)
  - Shockley, William, 1969-1970 (Folder 16: 12)
- Population reproduced tables and charts--all courses, 1940-1975 (Box-folder 17: 1-3)
- World Urbanization, 1950-1970 (Folder 17: 4-5)
  Volume II, chapters 1-9, office copy, 1969. Typescript
- Population and international relations--basic data, 1973 (Box-folder 18: 1-3)
- "Cities and Morality: International Population and Urban Research,", 1972 January. (Folder 18: 4)
- World Urbanization, 1950-1970 (Folder 18: 5)
  Volume 1, 1970 July. Typescript
- Analysis of Effects of Urbanization by Joseph Froomkin, 1952 February. (Folder 18: 6)
- Class tables, 1949-1975 (Box-folder 19: 1-3)
- Papers from Kingsley Davis as director, International Population and Urban Research (IPUR), University of California, Berkeley, 1965-1973. (Folder 19: 4-6)
  Includes lectures, pending manuscripts, and speeches
- Chronological correspondence file, 1974 July - October (Box-folder 20: 1-2)
- Writings by Kingsley Davis, 1974-1975 (Folder 20: 3-4)
- Writings by Kingsley Davis, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 21: 1)
- Chronological correspondence file
  - 1974 November - December (Folder 21: 2)
  - 1975
    - 1975 January - February (Folder 21: 3)
    - 1975 March - April (Folder 21: 4)
    - 1975 May - June (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - 1975 July - August (Folder 22: 2)
    - 1975 September - October (Folder 22: 3)
  - 1976 January - February (Folder 22: 4)
- Write-ups of the volumes in the Demography series, 1975 (Folder 22: 5)
- World Urbanization, 1950-1970, revision, 1973 June. (Box-folder 23: 1)
- Illegitimacy--project-matching tape and program, 1971-1973 (Folder 23: 2)
- Population--data, 1971-1972, and typescript chapters on population and family structure, undated (Folder 23: 3-5)
- Chronological correspondence file (Folder 24)
  - 1976
    - 1976 March - May (Folder 24: 1)
    - 1976 June - September (Folder 24: 2)
- Copies of lectures on population, 1966-1975 (Folder 24: 3)
- Honduras--population tables and graphs, 1966 (Folder 24: 4)
- Reprints of articles by Kingsley Davis, 1938-1973 (Box-folder 25: 1-3)
- International population and relation, 1973 June (Box-folder 26: 1-2)
- Federal census data, 1973 (Folder 26: 3-10)
- World Urbanization, 1950-1970, latest chapter carbons and miscellany, 1952 (Box-folder 27: 1)
- "Primary Cities: An International Analysis of First-City Primacy, 1965 June 28 (Folder 27: 2)
- Articles on population policy and migration, 1972-1974 (Folder 27: 3-5)
- World Urbanization, 1950-1970. (Box-folder 28: 1-6)
  Typescript. Includes latest original chapters, 1952-1957, and final manuscript, Volume II, 1970-1972
- Urban projections and related typescript chapters, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 29: 1-6)
- California Population Conference manuscript, 1971. (Box-folder 30: 1)
- World Urbanization, 1950-1970; 1967-1970. (Folder 30: 2-5)
- Scientific American articles, 1957-1965 (Folder 30: 6)
- Family planning history, 1940-1976 (Box-folder 31: 1-5)
- Cities by size, 1964-1970 (Folder 31: 6)
- World Urbanization, 1950-1970 (Box-folder 32: 1-3)
  Volume II, chapters 1-5
- Data on city population, 1970 (Folder 32: 4-7)
- International relations and population manuscripts, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 33: 1)
- California population, 1970-1971 (Folder 33: 2-4)
- Latin America--population and fertility data, 1950-1973 (Folder 33: 5)
- Migration, 1972 (Box-folder 34: 1-2)
- California study, 1971
  - Migrants and origin, Volume II (Folder 34: 3)
  - Age, sex, and ethnic group, Volume III (Folder 34: 4)
- Scientific American article, 1974 (Box-folder 35: 1)
- American Psychiatric Association, Detroit, 1974 May (Folder 35: 2)
- "Population Policy and Reproductive Motivation," article, American Journal of Psychiatry, 1974. (Folder 35: 3)
- Population Association of America meeting, New York, 1974 April (Folder 35: 4)
- American Association for the Advancement of Science, San Francisco, California, 1974 February 24 - March 1. (Folder 35: 5-6)
  Correspondence and program of the 140th meeting, 1974 February
- Conference on Latin American Education, University of Houston, Texas, 1973 October. (Folder 35: 7)
- State Social Welfare Board meeting, San Francisco, California, 1972 December 21-22 (Folder 35: 8)
- Science and Man in the Americas," Consejo Nacional de Ciencia y Technologia, American Association for the Advancement of Science meetings, Mexico City, 1973 June (Folder 35: 9)
- International Union for the Scientific Study of Population Conference, Liege, Belgium, 1973 September (Folder 35: 10)
- Southern Regional Demographic Group meeting, Atlanta, Georgia, 1973 October (Folder 35: 11)
- West Coast Conference of the World Population Society, California State University, Long Beach, 1975 (Box-folder 36: 1)
- Sociological Research Association meeting, San Francisco, California, 1975 August 27 (Folder 36: 2)
- American Sociological Association meeting, San Francisco, California, 1975 (Folder 36: 3)
- Meeting to evaluate the Program to Improve the Dissemination of Research Results to California State Government, 1975 September 4 (Folder 36: 4)
- International seminar on Bangladesh population policies, 1975 May 15-21 (Folder 36: 5)
- "Asia's Cities: Problems and Options," Population and Development Review, 1975 (Folder 36: 6)
- Claim form for reimbursement for attending a meeting of the Aging Review Committee, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, 1975 May 15-16 (Folder 36: 7)
- "Population in the Context of Development," paper for Population Council, 1975 June. (Folder 36: 8)
- Census Advisory Committee meeting, Washington, D.C., 1975 May 3-4 (Folder 36: 9)
  (folder empty)
- Census Advisory Committee on Population Statistics meeting, Bureau of the Census, Suitland, Maryland, 1975 April 4 (Folder 36: 10)
- Testimony in reference to A.B. 781, Sacramento, California, 1975 April 8 (Folder 36: 11)
- American Academy of Arts and Sciences Class III Subcommittee Membership meeting, Boston, Massachusetts, 1974 November 19 (Folder 36: 12)
- "Population Growth in Developing Areas: Future Trends and Prospects," Michigan State University, 1975 May 21 (Folder 36: 13)
- Bay Area Psychiatric Association dinner, 1975 March 11 (Folder 36: 14)
- NAS Nominating Committee meeting, Washington, D.C., 1975 January 18. (Folder 36: 15)
  Itinerary only
- Symposium on "A Growing and Hungry World," Tarrant County Junior College District, Texas, 1975 April 24-25. (Folder 36: 16)
- Population Association of America annual meeting, Seattle, Washington, 1975 April 17-19 (Folder 36: 17)
- American Academy of Arts and Sciences Class III meeting, 1975 April 3 (Folder 36: 18)
- American Academy of Arts and Sciences meeting of the nominating committee, Boston, 1975 April 3 (Folder 36: 19)
- Conference on the Satisfaction and Value of Children, sponsored by the Behavioral Sciences Branch of the Center for Population Research, National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, Belmont, 1974 October 9-11 (Folder 36: 20)
- World Food, Population, and Resources Program, San Francisco State University, California, 1975 Fall (Folder 36: 21)
- "Asia's Cities: Problems and Options," inaugural lecture, Asia Society's program on the Asian City, 1974 October 23-25. (Folder 36: 22)
- Symposium on Material Shortages for Senator John Tunney, University of California, Berkeley, 1975 January 13 (Folder 36: 23)
- "The Demographic Fly in the Ointment," lecture, University of Utah, 1974 October 11. (Folder 36: 24)
- Census Advisory Committee on Population Statistics, Suitland, Maryland, 1974 October 3-4 (Folder 36: 25)
- Expense report for Kingsley Davis's trip to Tel Aviv, Israel, 1974 July (Folder 36: 26)
- Expense reports for Kingsley Davis's trips to Paris, France, and Barcelona, Spain, 1974 July (Folder 36: 27)
- Polish Conference on Migration, Warsaw, Poland, 1974 June 27 - July 2. (Folder 36: 28-29)
- Mc--Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 37: 1)
- The Macmillan Company, 1953 (Folder 37: 2)
- New York Times, 1951-1954 (Folder 37: 3)
- N--Miscellaneous, 1949-1954. (Folder 37: 4)
- "Some Principles of Stratification," co-authored with Wilbert E. Moore, American Sociological Review, 1945 April. (Folder 37: 5)
- "The World Demographic Transition," The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1945 January. (Folder 37: 6)
- "Adolescence and the Social Structure," The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1944 November. (Folder 37: 7)
- "Children of Divorced Parents: A Sociological and Statistical Analysis," Law and Contemporary Problems, 1944 summer. (Folder 37: 8)
- "Extreme Social Isolation of a Child," The American Journal of Sociology, 1940 January. (Folder 37: 9)
- "The Sociology of Parent-Youth Conflict," American Sociological Review, 1940 August. (Folder 37: 10)
- "The Child and the Social Structure," Journal of Educational Sociology, 1940 December. (Folder 37: 11)
- "The Forms of Illegitimacy," Social Forces, 1939 October. (Folder 37: 12)
- "Illegitimacy and the Social Structure," American Journal of Sociology, 1939 September. (Folder 37: 13)
  Printed abstract
- "Mental Hygiene and the Class Structure," Psychiatry: Journal of the Biology and Pathology of Interpersonal Relations, 1938 February. (Folder 37: 14)
- "Reproductive Institutions and the Pressure for Population," The Sociological Review, 1937 July. (Folder 37: 15)
- "The Sociology of Prostitution," American Sociological Review, 1937 October. (Folder 37: 16)
- "An Attempt to Discover Change in Moral Attitudes of High-School Students," co-authored with Joseph K. Johnson, International Journal of Ethics, 1934 January. (Folder 37: 17)
- Participant, "American Society on Trial," San Jose State University, California, 1975 September 11 - December 4 (Folder 37: 18)
- Food and Agriculture Conference on population and labor-force projections, Rome, Italy, 1975 October 13-15 (Folder 37: 19)
- Expense reports
  - Trip to India, 1975 December (Folder 37: 20)
  - Trip to Nepal for workshop--conference on "Family Planning, Population, and Development in Nepal,", 1975-1976 (Folder 37: 21)
  - Trip to Iran, 1975 (Folder 37: 22)
- Meeting called by Jones(?) in president's(?) office, 1975 September (Folder 37: 23)
- Census Advisory Committee meeting on population statistics, 1975 October 17 (Folder 37: 24)
- Conference on "Crises 1975," California State University, Fresno, California, 1975 Spring (Folder 37: 25)
- International Sponsoring Committee for the Chaim Weizmann Centenary celebration (1974-1975), 1974 July (Folder 37: 26)
- Personal correspondence, 1935-1955 (Box-folder 38: 1)
- Malthus, 1950-1954 (Folder 38: 2)
- National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, 1978 (Folder 38: 3)
- The Pathfinder Fund, 1978 (Folder 38: 4)
- Petersen, William, 1977 (Folder 38: 5)
- Population Policy Training Program, undated (Folder 38: 6)
- Population Resource Center, 1979 (Folder 38: 7)
- The Population Council, 1978 (Folder 38: 8)
- Publication outlets, 1977-1979 (Folder 38: 9)
- Ravenholt, R. T., 1976-1977 (Folder 38: 10)
- Padmanabha, P., 1977 (Folder 38: 11)
  (reprint list)
- Reprint of Kingsley Davis's material, 1974-1978 (Folder 38: 12)
- Riley, Matilda White, 1977 (Folder 38: 13)
- Scientific American reader on population, 1977 (Folder 38: 14)
- Mailing list, 1977 (Folder 38: 15)
- Mayo Clinic, 1978-1979 (Folder 38: 16)
- Mother's Age, 1977-1980 (Folder 38: 17)
- Stone, Linda, undated (Folder 38: 18)
- Subscriptions--Journals, 1978 (Folder 38: 19)
- Population Association of America, 1973 (Folder 38: 20)
  (theory session)
- Application for Graduate Programs of Master of Public Administration with a Specialization in Population Studies and Master of Public Administration with a Specialization in Population Policy, School of Public Administration and Department of Sociology (Population Research Laboratory), University of Southern California, Los Angeles, undated (Folder 38: 21)
- United Nations expenses, 1979 (Folder 38: 22)
- University of Southern California, 1977-1979 (Folder 38: 23)
- Treas, Judy, 1977 (Folder 38: 24)
- California--data on population, 1971 (Folder 38: 25)
- O--Miscellaneous, 1949-1955. (Folder 38: 26)
- Singh, Sushila, 1977 (Folder 38: 27)
- Personal--Publicity, 1944-1953 (Folder 38: 28)
- Sociological Inquiry, 1977 (Folder 38: 29)
- Sklar, June, undated (Folder 38: 30)
- Department of Sociology and Anthropology, 1977-1979 (Folder 38: 31)
- Sociological Research Association, 1979 (Folder 38: 32)
- Spencer, Gregory Kincaid, 1977 (Folder 38: 33)
- Refinement of Rank Correlation of Cities by Carl Hammer, Urbanization Project, Bureau of Applied Social Research, Columbia University, New York, 1951 October 18. (Box-folder 39: 1)
  Typescript partial progress report number 2
- "Urbanism," Proceedings of the University Seminar on Population, 1950-1951, Bureau of Applied Social Research, Columbia University, New York, 1951 September. (Folder 39: 2)
  Typescript summary
- Book reviews and articles, 1952-1955 (Folder 39: 3-4)
- Blake, Judith, 1954 (Folder 39: 5)
- I--Miscellaneous, 1951-1954. (Folder 39: 6)
- International Population--Book project (Folder 39: 7)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, J-L, 1949-1955 (Folder 39: 8-10)
- Daily sheets, 1953 July 1 - December 31 (Box-folder 40: 1)
- Correspondence, 1952 July 1 - December 31 (Folder 40: 2)
- Review of Josue de Castro, The Geography of Hunger, 1952. (Folder 40: 3)
- Miscellaneous correspondence
  - A-D, 1949-1955 (Folder 40: 4-7)
  - 1953 January 1 - June 30 (Folder 40: 8)
- Africa, 1952
  - Daily diary. (Folder 40: 9)
    Includes some photographs
  - Interview notes. (Folder 40: 10)
- Daily sheets, 1954 November – 1955 April (Box-folder 41: 1)
- Miscellany, E-H, 1949-1955. (Folder 41: 2-5)
- Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1955 (Folder 41: 6)
- Human Society, 1949-1953 (Folder 41: 7)
- Correspondence--Miscellaneous, 1948 (Folder 41: 8)
- Daily sheets, 1954 January 15 - October 26 (Folder 41: 9-10)
- Data on urbanization, undated; correspondence, 1953-1954; a typescript outline for an article on Jamaica Project, undated; and a typescript article, "Population and Resources: A Plan for Research (Box-folder 42: 1-3)
- Correspondence
  - 1953-1954 (Folder 42: 4)
    (Jamaica)
  - 1959 October -, 1961 November - December (Folder 42: 5)
  - 1962 March (Folder 42: 6)
- Copies of lectures (urban), 1965-1975 (Box-folder 43: 1)
- Africa trip diary, 1952 (Folder 43: 2)
  The diary of Davis' 1952 journey through Africa consists of 114 typewritten pages dating from October 2nd to December 5th 1952, and contains descriptions of the following countries: Democratic Republic of Congo, Republic of Congo, Burundi, Rwanda, Uganda, Angola, Cameroon, Gabon, Nigeria, Ghana, and Ivory Coast. Urban development within Africa is discussed extensively, and includes Davis's observations of the following cities: Leopoldville (now Kinshasa), Elizabethville (now Lubumbashi), Costermansville (now Bukavu), Usumbura (now Bujumbura), Astrida (now Butare), Kigali, Butembo, Brazzaville, Luanda, Douala, Libreville, Yaounde, Lagos, Ibadan, Kano, Kaduna, Accra, Kumasi, Tarkwa, Takoradi, and Abidjan. Other content of the diary examines traditional native cultures, colonial administration, regional economies, business enterprises, race relations, climate, and other topics.
- Mediterranean, 1968-1974 (Folder 43: 3)
- Bahrain, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 44: 1-3)
- California
  - 1970-2000 (Folder 44: 4)
  - 1978 (Folder 44: 5)
    (Birth registration)
  - Undated (Folder 44: 6-7)
    (Population Project, Chapter II)
  - Undated (Folder 44: 8)
    (California study)
- Correspondence, 1970 (Box-folder 45: 1)
- Sociology 230--Hand outs, 1977 Winter (Folder 45: 2)
- Hewlett Foundation, 1977-1982 (Folder 45: 3)
- Nomination for the conferment of an honorary degree, University of Southern California, 1979-1981 (Folder 45: 4)
- Brochure and course description, Department of Demography, University of California, Berkeley, 1970-1971 (Folder 45: 5)
- Jacob, Jim, 1950-1969 (Folder 45: 6)
- Divorced fathers--arranging funds for a book of case studies of divorces involving children, Department of Sociology, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, 1977-1978 (Folder 45: 7)
- Endowment project--Chair in Population/Ecology, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, 1977 (Folder 45: 8)
- "Family Formation and Fertility: Key Trends and Patterns," final report, principal investigator, Kingsley Davis, University of California, Berkeley, 1972 October – 1977 February. (Folder 45: 9)
  Includes a letter to Luis Angelone, 1969
- Financial statement of Kingsley Davis re: Ford Foundation grant, 1977 (Folder 45: 10)
- Proposal by the Regents of the University of California to the Ford Foundation requesting support for a training and research project entitled: "An Expanded International Training and Research Program in Population," for the period from, 1968 July 1 – 1973 June 30 (Folder 45: 11)
- A Study of Childlessness and One-Child Families--a project proposal submitted by International Population and Urban Research (IPUR), University of California, Berkeley, 1974 (Folder 45: 12)
- Final summary report and comprehensive report for the project, "A Study of Childlessness and One-Child Families,", 1977-1978 (Folder 45: 13)
- "Childless Women," June Sklar, International Population and Urban Research (IPUR) and Department of Demography, University of California, Berkeley, 1971 April (Folder 45: 14)
- A Proposal for research on comparative levels and trends in childlessness and one-child families, 1977 September 19
- California, 1971-1972.
  Typescript and holograph
  - Data on population (Folder 45: 15-17)
  - "Changing Composition of the Population," Chapter III (Folder 45: 18)
  - Urbanization (Folder 45: 19)
- "The Theory of Change and Response in Modern Demographic History,", 1963. (Box-folder 46: 1)
- "Social Demography," lecture, Voice of America Forum, Behavioral Sciences, 1963. (Folder 46: 2)
- "Population," paper, Population Growth in Man, XVI International Congress of Zoology proceedings, Volume 9, Washington, D.C., 1963. (Folder 46: 3)
- "The Corporate Image in Social Context: The Problem of Demographic Change,", 1963. (Folder 46: 4)
- "Norms, Values, and Sanctions," co-authored with Judith Blake, Handbook of Modern Sociology, 1964. (Folder 46: 5)
- "Demographic and Social Changes in the Next 25 Years," paper, Motivations and Methods in Development and Foreign Aid, Sixth World Conference, Society for International Development, 1964. (Folder 46: 6)
- "Some Demographic Aspects of Poverty in the United States,", 1965. (Folder 46: 7)
- Rural/Urban, India, 1946-1959 (Folder 46: 8)
- "The Confusion of Prosperity with Economic Expanses," excerpts, 16th Annual Riecker Lecture, University of Arizona, 1972 May 10. (Folder 46: 9)
- "Environment of Federal Operations," participant, U. S. Civil Service Commission's Executive Seminar, Executive Seminar Center, University of California, Berkeley, 1972 April 21. (Folder 46: 10)
  Correspondence and program only
- "The Birth Rate and Public Welfare in California," testimony, State Social Welfare Board, San Mateo, California, 1972 July 28. (Folder 46: 11)
- "The Early Marriage Trend," What's New, 1958 Fall. (Box-folder 47: 1)
- "Convention versus Metropolitan Data in the International Study of Urbanization," American Sociological Review, 1958. (Folder 47: 2)
- "Report on the World Social Situation," co-authored with Hilda Hertz, United Nations, New York, 1957. (Folder 47: 3)
- "Urban Demography and Ecology," Alpha Kappa Deltan, 1958 Winter. (Folder 47: 4)
- "The Demographic Consequences of Changes in Productive Technology: An Essay on the Problem of Measurement," Social, Economic and Technological Change, 1958. (Folder 47: 5)
- "The Myth of Functional Analysis as a Special Method in Sociology and Anthropology," presidential address, annual meeting of the American Sociological Association, Chicago, 1959 September. (Folder 47: 6)
  Printed copy, American Sociological Review, 1959 December
- "The Sociology of Demographic Behavior," Sociology Today: Problems and Prospects, Basic Books, 1959. (Folder 47: 7)
- "Recent Population Trends in the New World: An Over-all View," Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1958 March. (Folder 47: 8)
- "Population Analysis and Social Behavior,", 1960(?). (Folder 47: 9)
- "Population and Welfare in Industrial Societies," Fourth Annual Dorothy Nyswander Lecture, Berkeley, California, Health, Education Monographs, 1960 April 6. (Folder 47: 10)
- "Birth Control and Public Policy," co-authored with Judith Blake, Commentary, 1960 February. (Folder 47: 11)
- "Urbanization in India: Past and Future," paper, seminar on Urbanization in India, 1962. (Folder 47: 12)
- "American Society and Its Group Structure," Contemporary Civilization, 1961. (Folder 47: 13)
- "Population and Sex,", 1961. (Folder 47: 14)
- "Tendencias Demograficas Recientes en el Nuevo Mundo-UNA Vision General," Estadistica, Journal of the Inter-American Statistical Institute, 1960 December. (Folder 47: 15)
- "New Population Trends," The Liberal Papers, edited by James Roosevelt, 1962. (Folder 47: 16)
- "The Causes and Effects of First-City Primacy with Special Reference to Latin America," paper, Hermosillo, Mexico, 1962 November. (Folder 47: 17)
- "The Role of Class Mobility in Economic Development," speech, Institute of International Studies, University of California, Berkeley, 1962. (Folder 47: 18)
- "Future Demographic Growth of the San Francisco Bay Area," co-authored with Eleanor Langlois, Institute of Governmental Studies, University of California, Berkeley, 1963 February 1. (Folder 47: 19)
- Book on population (?), draft chapters, undated. (Box-folder 48: 1)
- "Values, Population, and the Supernatural: A Critique,", 1949. (Folder 48: 2)
- "Sociological Approach: Discussion I," Psychosexual Development in Health and Disease, 1949. (Folder 48: 3)
- "Population and Resources in the Americas," paper, Inter-American Conference on Conservation of Renewable Natural Resources, Denver, Colorado, 1948 September 7-20. (Folder 48: 4)
- "Future Migration into Latin America," Milbank Memorial Fund Quarterly, 1947 January. (Folder 48: 5)